# Uchechukwu Okeke

# Software Engineer

Atlanta, GA | (678)914-3918 | robinsonokeke60@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio / GitHub

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over 4+ years of experience in Front End Development, Responsive Web Design, Analysis, Development, Implementation and testing of Web applications as a Web Developer using JavaScript, AngularJS (1.x), React.js, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, NodeJS, jQuery, AJAX. Exposure on Python Development. Experience on complete Software development life cycle (SDLC) with software development.

### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Python, Figma, SQL, React, Node.js, Express.js, Jquery, Django, MongoDB, Mongoose, postgres, RESTful API's, JSON, GitHub, EJS, AJAX, Sandbox, Adobe acrobat, AzureDevop

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**1ST FRANKLIN FINANCIAL - Toccoa, GA Aug 2022 – Present** Software Developer ◆ Performs Design and Architecture Functions, Writes code, analyze data and data flow to contribute to software design and implementation as needed, review code work for accuracy and functionality of IT staff

- Participates in and as needed, leads the analysis, and development of innovative solutions and refinement and optimization of existing system
- Wrote Python routines to log into the websites and fetch data for selected options. Collaborates with team members and business clients to propose solutions and resolve day to day issues and participates or conducts testing to include unit testing, integration testing, performance testing, system testing or user acceptance testing as required

**ALCON - Johns Creek, GA Aug 2021 - Present** *Front End Developer) (Part Time)* ● Boosted production by 30 percent by figuring out a more efficient way to operate machinery which led to over 10,000 lenses per shift

- Assisted in Front End Development of web application with REACT.js/ HTML/CSS/javaScript for company
- Maximized responsibility by being an efficient team member through teamwork and problem solving, taking initiative to assist colleagues when they are faced with a challenge

#### ANOTHER CHANCE - Decatur, GA Oct 2018 - Aug 2022 Front End Engineer

- Utilized tools like React libraries and CSS libraries to create cohesive edits that can be picked up by other engineers.
- Designed the front end of the application using Python, Java, Html, CSS.
- Develops data-driven web applications and finds efficient solutions.
- Support website planning and deployment.
- Maintain a functioning user-accessible website
- Code less complex websites using HTML, Visual Basic, or other web-based programming languages Worked Closely with the design team, implementing foundational styles and interacting with Figma designs to create front end experiences

#### **Projects**

Sleep tracker (Django, React.js, PostgresQL, javaScript, CSS, Bcrypt)

- Developed and designed a full-stack web app with a team of 3 following full RESTful API routing and giving user the ability to track sleep hour, routine and input diary
  - Incorporated user authentication, which allows user to get, input, update and delete data which are stored in a postgresQl database, user can also delete personal account and all saved data
     Utilized GitHub to merge individual branches to the dev branch and resolved all merge conflicts

Staff App (HTML5, CSS3, Express, Node.is, EJS, Mongoose & MongoDB)

• Created and designed a full-stack web app following full RESTful routing and giving the user access to full CRUD functionality, users can add, remove, edit or delete staff 's information • Saved user input through the server-side Mongoose database using MongoDB

Real Estate listing App (JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS3, Express, Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB/Atlas and Heroku )

- Built and designed a full-stack web app following full RESTful routing and giving the user access to full CRUD functionality
- Coordinated with partner to build the initial React App.js base and then evenly divided the rest into two
  components house.js and condo.js with each component containing its own hook, function, and JSX
  and communicating for a constant view and feel across the application

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **General Assembly Online 2022**

Software Engineering Immersive Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team Collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects. Atlanta Metropolitan State University - Atlanta, GA Aug 2020 Application Development Certificate Program - 400+ hour

**High school**Greenforest Christian Academy